<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?Xpress productLine="standard-clause" ?><clause xmlns:xt="urn:xpressauthor:trackchanges" author="Kieran O'Donnell" dateTime="2021-03-29T09:06:33" id="_520db1d9-a633-4ac9-8c88-a960a99371f2" outputclass="standard-clause" type="insert"><sptc>1.1</sptc><title id="_19cf45dd-e4c8-4f2b-aef1-bd5ac0a4d780">Step-free access path</title><ol outputclass="numbered"><li id="_6e6ff30e-9e72-405a-b30e-74ea5a18482b">A continuous path to a dwelling entrance door must be provided from—<ol><li id="_ebeb7359-fee2-4a57-9da5-e1503ba88b73">the pedestrian entry at the allotment boundary from the ground level of the adjoining land; or</li><li>an appurtenant Class 10a garage or carport; or</li><li>a car parking space within the allotment that is provided for the exclusive use of the occupants of the dwelling.</li></ol></li><li id="_44b2364d-69bf-4d6b-bc98-9c671b461d10">Access for the purposes of (1) must be—<ol><li id="_72e3a95b-1bd7-4fc2-9db6-201a2a00b9cf">via a pathway that—<ol><li>has no steps; and</li><li>except for a step ramp provided under (5), has a maximum gradient of 1:14 in the direction of travel; and</li><li>if crossfall is provided, has a crossfall not steeper than 1:40; and</li><li>has a minimum width of 1000 mm; and</li><li>if it incorporates a section suspended above finished ground level, is able to take loading forces in accordance with AS/NZS 1170.1; and</li><li>connects to a dwelling entrance door that complies with Section 2; or</li></ol></li><li>provided directly from an attached Class 10a garage or carport, via a door complying with the requirements of Section 2, other than <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/2abe2d62-a871-4509-969b-2425466626a4/5020_0.21.0.xml#_e8f7abbb-b483-4b6f-9cff-a774fa1eb109" id="_83723ee8-fd37-408c-9d3f-12ee4e2657a9" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="standard-clause">Clause 2.3</xref>.</li></ol></li><li id="_1195f89a-646b-4a19-8b85-a9a7d0f9916f">For the purposes of (2), the following applies:<ol><li id="_09e1185b-dca4-4a6f-b94e-2685c5867b86">Any gates along the access path must have a minimum clear opening width of 820 mm, measured as if the gate were an entrance door.</li><li>A deck or boardwalk-style path constructed in accordance with AS 1684 or NASH Standard – Residential and Low-rise Steel Framing would satisfy the requirements of (2)(a)(v).</li></ol></li><li id="_e4fcc060-e43d-496a-a80a-b9c80a63b631">Where one or more ramps are used, the following applies:<ol><li id="_0df9ba21-c434-4905-9aa6-3b02d76bd6e7">The aggregate length of ramping (excluding landings) must not be more than—<ol><li>9 m for a 1:14 gradient; or</li><li>15 m for a 1:20 gradient; or</li><li>a length determined by linear interpolation for ramps with a gradient between 1:14 and 1:20.</li></ol></li><li>The minimum width of the ramp must be maintained at 1000 mm between any handrails and/or kerbs (if provided) at each side of the ramp.</li><li>At each end of a ramp there must be a landing that is—<ol><li>not less than 1200 mm long; and</li><li>at least as wide as the ramp to which it connects; and</li><li>level, or has a gradient not steeper than 1:40 if a gradient is necessary for drainage.</li></ol></li><li>A landing area required by <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/2abe2d62-a871-4509-969b-2425466626a4/5020_0.21.0.xml#_e8f7abbb-b483-4b6f-9cff-a774fa1eb109" id="_97297e72-874c-4790-83e4-d40c3394946d" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="standard-clause">Clause 2.3</xref> may also be counted as a landing for the purposes of (c).</li></ol></li><li id="_0d0712c0-2f49-4047-ad31-e6b42e9a4150">The access path may incorporate one step ramp having a—<ol><li id="_fd188891-0f26-40e8-81b6-4c093aa1e39f">height of not more than 190 mm; and</li><li>gradient not more than 1:10; and</li><li>width of at least 1000 mm or equivalent to that of the access path, whichever is the greater; and</li><li>maximum length of 1900 mm.</li></ol></li></ol><callout id="_99e571de-591a-486e-a8ff-81918781e2d4"><callout-type info-type="application"/><p>Clause 1.1 only applies to a Class 1a building.</p></callout><callout id="_575aee8f-51fb-4cac-a16b-f4329f687c8b"><callout-type info-type="info"/><title id="_04fa9931-a245-4f09-9688-b97375948c05">Access via a garage, carport or parking space</title><p>Where step-free access is provided from a garage, carport or parking space, this can be through a connecting door between the garage, carport or parking space and the dwelling. The connecting door need not be the main entrance door (sometimes referred to as the ‘front’ door) but would need to comply with Section 2. Any carparking spaces forming part of the required path of travel must be free of obstructions, including structural elements such as columns or engaged brick piers that would otherwise reduce the space for free movement.</p></callout><callout id="_1212a8a9-c58e-4ba3-a6d5-995aee1e9152"><callout-type info-type="info"/><title id="_47b0a53b-ace8-45e1-a8d7-56c1cc6196ff">Class 2 buildings</title><p>For a Class 2 building, requirements for a step-free access path are provided in Section D of NCC Volume One and the ‘Disability (Access to Premises — Buildings) Standards 2010’. Therefore, Clause 1.1 only applies to Class 1a buildings.</p></callout></clause>