<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?Xpress productLine="page" ?><page xmlns:xt="urn:xpressauthor:trackchanges" id="_7cd59d4a-78e1-4e11-98f3-0c8f2e32833b" outputclass="page"><title id="_60508571-6969-4750-98f7-3d5dbba4384f">Introduction</title><section id="_0178677a-ad6b-4840-8716-f895df0cd8ac"><title id="_eea3e5ca-f86d-4ecd-b32f-8ce8884a2b3b">Background</title><p>This ABCB Standard provides a set of technical provisions that if complied with will enable dwellings to better meet the needs of the community, including older people and people with mobility limitations.</p><p>This ABCB Standard has been adapted from the ‘Silver’ level requirements of the Livable Housing Design Guidelines (LHDG), fourth edition, 2017, which were first published by Livable Housing Australia.</p><p>It is important to note that this ABCB Standard is not an exact replication of the LHDG. There are instances where adjustments have been made in order to convert the LHDG — which was drafted as a voluntary guideline — into a document suitable for use as a regulatory standard. There are also instances where adjustments have been made in response to stakeholder feedback provided through one or more of the consultation processes that occurred in the development of this document.</p></section><section id="_3c236f5d-7939-466f-a67f-3a0632ad8144"><title id="_8233a99a-c184-47d9-ab18-ee509b88e565">Scope</title><p>This ABCB Standard is intended as a set of minimum necessary provisions, rather than as an exemplar of best practice. This is consistent with the role of the National Construction Code (NCC) which calls up this ABCB Standard.</p><p>This ABCB Standard is not intended for use in designing specialist accommodation, nor is it intended to achieve equivalence with AS 1428.1. Therefore, its provisions may not accommodate the needs and abilities of all home occupants. Nonetheless, the features described herein are considered to be of most widespread benefit and use in the majority of circumstances.</p></section><section id="_79ccfaf8-2d96-42b4-81c1-dcbbef49ec2a"><title id="_0c49a199-47d6-4a58-816a-366efbb991b8">Application</title><p>In this ABCB Standard, generic references are made to ‘dwellings’. The specific application of this ABCB Standard to particular types of dwelling is determined according to the particular regulation or guideline in which the ABCB Standard may be referenced.</p><p>In general, the provisions of this ABCB Standard are designed for application to Class 1a buildings (houses and the like) and Class 2 <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/2abe2d62-a871-4509-969b-2425466626a4/1473_0.4.0.xml#_d2c89488-8a36-464b-94f6-a91d0f5a6c9c" id="_06c441d7-05f3-4851-8d90-b9a206b052c1" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="abcb-glossentry">sole-occupancy units</xref> (apartments), as defined in the NCC.</p><p>This ABCB Standard is referenced in the <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/2abe2d62-a871-4509-969b-2425466626a4/1236_1.0.0.xml#_2f02788f-8757-4689-b36e-e44d96524cc9" id="_4b9a0098-688c-48cd-b35a-cf86a67b7ca0" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="abcb-glossentry">Deemed-to-Satisfy Provisions</xref> of <xref format="dita" href="qpp://assets/4928#_874b81e6-f2cd-49e6-a2c5-c85b04e85069" id="_032884a3-0a3b-4bd3-8af6-e1f189e59cf5" publishing-id="vol1" referencetype="Text" scope="external" synctargettext="false" type="ncc-part">Part G7</xref> of NCC Volume One and <xref format="dita" href="qpp://assets/4936#_ec0ebc74-a071-443f-8c89-69eea67e5077" id="_64908cd5-e493-41a4-a747-664decfd0409" publishing-id="vol2" referencetype="Text" scope="external" synctargettext="false" type="ncc-part">Part H8</xref> of NCC Volume Two.</p><p>This ABCB Standard is not intended to be read in isolation and must only be used in conjunction with the relevant Part of the NCC.</p><p>The ABCB has also published a non-mandatory version of this ABCB Standard based on the LHDG ‘Gold’ level requirements, which can be applied on a voluntary basis to achieve a higher level of livability.</p></section><section id="_c3440070-2ce0-4f67-ae30-571926160c48"><title id="_f9689302-9757-4361-9662-beb0b2055e9c">Terms with a specific meaning</title><p>In this ABCB Standard, terms shown in italicised text have the meaning that they have in the NCC.</p></section><section id="_de49057f-2544-4890-b854-24156f8fcaea"><title id="_cf8ffa33-2fd3-49b9-8a15-f43050f48410">Version history</title><p>The version history is outlined <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/2abe2d62-a871-4509-969b-2425466626a4/8923_0.8.0.xml#_24a2e8f9-d794-4340-a938-8d9ec21257de" id="_6eee2aa9-4514-46dc-bf41-e9fda20b468b" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="table-reference">Table 1</xref>. This version supersedes all previous versions from its release date.</p><table-reference conref="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/2abe2d62-a871-4509-969b-2425466626a4/8923_0.8.0.xml" graph="None" id="_24a2e8f9-d794-4340-a938-8d9ec21257de"><num/><title id="_03f0e1ad-805b-45a0-b8d0-44197c912654"/></table-reference></section></page>