<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?Xpress productLine="ncc-clause" ?><clause xmlns:xt="urn:xpressauthor:trackchanges" id="_c4e40987-aaaa-421b-9625-4025a3ef68d5" outputclass="ncc-clause"><sptc>B2D3</sptc><title id="_574db316-59e0-4e4a-9800-862f88392f79">Layout of taps</title><archive-num>2019: B2.3</archive-num><subclause id="_6c679f05-318e-482e-8206-6b95885fcffc" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_3004c642-96e1-4191-aa69-1328b246bf2c">SubClause</title><num>1</num><p>Where both a <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1334_0.4.0.xml#_92b3a3dc-59e4-425f-909b-d8eb03e6460a" id="_83dd37ee-0c93-4e0a-acb5-234c4ab21f22" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">heated water</xref> tap and a cold water tap are installed, the <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1334_0.4.0.xml#_92b3a3dc-59e4-425f-909b-d8eb03e6460a" id="_c014b034-2634-4916-ac16-7f55f09fa5fa" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">heated water</xref> tap must be installed to the left of, or above, the cold water tap if—</p><ol outputclass="alpha"><li id="_05024f52-1f6b-4bc3-9001-0280569589c7">each tap controls a separate outlet; or</li><li id="_4dc27aac-df9c-4a6c-be64-1c135d485a8d">both taps control a combined flow of water delivered through a single outlet.</li></ol></subclause><callout id="_3a37f99c-f5a9-4de2-93a2-4bcdc688426e"><callout-type ncc-info-type="info"/><p>To reduce the likelihood of scalding in a bath, consideration should be given to installing taps out of reach of the bath occupants. This would reduce the likelihood of children accidentally turning the <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1334_0.4.0.xml#_92b3a3dc-59e4-425f-909b-d8eb03e6460a" id="_626da2b7-de27-41df-901a-bfb2d94d116b" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">heated water</xref> on or adjusting the water temperature.</p><p>To reduce the likelihood of scalding, consideration should be given to the following when installing <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1334_0.4.0.xml#_92b3a3dc-59e4-425f-909b-d8eb03e6460a" id="_2cc4eed3-e374-47cd-97d3-9ce6387f0d56" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">heated water</xref> taps in a shower:</p><ul><li><xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1334_0.4.0.xml#_92b3a3dc-59e4-425f-909b-d8eb03e6460a" id="_fc59045e-4c99-43b0-9e17-744081f5ecd5" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="abcb-glossentry">Heated water</xref> taps such as a quarter turn tap should be located in a manner, that to be turned on, requires the tap lever to be turned upwards, reducing the likelihood of accidentally turning the <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1334_0.4.0.xml#_92b3a3dc-59e4-425f-909b-d8eb03e6460a" id="_63f039f6-e898-431f-81be-a99e3cb55b5f" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">heated water</xref> on in the event of a slip or fall. Likewise, cold water taps should be located in a manner, so that the lever operator is turned down to turn on the cold water.</li><li>Mixing taps, where the lever is lifted to start the flow of water, should be considered because if a slip or fall occurred, there is greater likelihood that the temperature would either be reduced or the tap turned off.</li><li>The location of shower taps should be positioned at a height so that they cannot be operated by young children. </li><li>Positioning the taps in a specific recess may reduce the likelihood of accidentally altering the water temperature in the event of a slip or fall and is considered a suitable recommendation for bathrooms provided for the elderly or infirm.</li></ul></callout></clause>