<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?Xpress productLine="ncc-clause" ?><clause xmlns:xt="urn:xpressauthor:trackchanges" id="_fe0463c4-b3a1-49aa-b430-e4f6fb3222d0" outputclass="ncc-clause" variation="NSW"><sptc>C2D4</sptc><title id="_58495609-46b0-4b3b-a5eb-c723f8d8f330">General requirements</title><archive-num>2019: NSW C2.4</archive-num><subclause id="_37c4c8ea-8fda-4ca6-9f70-ea965dabd982" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_612d14f1-b84f-4cb6-961c-df9d9646586b">SubClause</title><num>1</num><p>A sanitary <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1249_0.8.0.xml#_25307451-c7e1-4167-b4de-e5a1af26694c" id="_a99ae49c-dcf0-4a68-acb9-add82dcab216" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">drainage</xref> system must be in accordance with AS/NZS 3500.2 with the following variations:</p><p>(a) Clause 4.3.1 insert subclause: (i) Shall not have DN40 or DN50 traps installed.</p><p>(b) Clause 4.4.1 insert the following as the second paragraph: Boundary trap or inspection shafts shall not terminate within:</p><p>(i) Bedrooms</p><p>(ii) Living rooms</p><p>(iii) Lounge rooms</p><p>(iv) Music rooms</p><p>(v) Television rooms</p><p>(vi) Kitchens</p><p>(vii) Dining rooms</p><p>(viii) Sewing rooms</p><p>(ix) Study</p><p>(x) Playroom</p><p>(xi) Family room</p><p>(xii) Home theatre room</p><p>(xiii) Sunroom</p><p>(xiv) Bathroom</p><p>(xv) Laundry</p><p>(xvi) Water closet</p><p>(xvii) Pantry</p><p>(xviii) Walk-in wardrobe</p><p>(xix) Corridor</p><p>(xx) Hallway</p><p>(xxi) Lobby</p><p>(xxii) Photographic darkroom</p><p>(xxii) Clothes drying room; and</p><p>(xxiv) Other spaces of a specialised nature occupied neither frequently nor for extended periods.</p><p>(c) Clause 4.5.2 insert subclause: (c) Soil and waste stacks shall not discharge through a reflux valve except where a reflux valve is installed at the connection to the sewer <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1432_4.0.0.xml#_af6fde9f-147d-4782-8b85-42044e80fd42" id="_b6798708-50aa-4add-9e3d-e8e3a19a3f0f" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="abcb-glossentry">required</xref> with surcharging sewers or where a <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1376_4.2.0.xml#_12d6153c-4986-4856-80c0-e21bb57af12f" id="_ae6e1852-9df8-4769-bbea-729bd9120cde" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="abcb-glossentry">Network Utility Operator</xref> may prescribe soffit requirements.</p><p>NOTE: Where the <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1376_4.2.0.xml#_12d6153c-4986-4856-80c0-e21bb57af12f" id="_337a85b6-bb20-4f20-817a-331a121101dc" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="abcb-glossentry">Network Utility Operator</xref> prescribes a reflux valves to be installed for Soffit Requirements, the <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1376_4.2.0.xml#_12d6153c-4986-4856-80c0-e21bb57af12f" id="_aa1f3051-500c-4c21-a392-f1e7968a5acd" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="abcb-glossentry">Network Utility Operator</xref> is responsible for the regulation of the reflux valve.</p><p>(d) Clause 4.5.3 delete and insert: Where a surcharge is likely to occur a reflux valve shall be installed immediately downstream of the boundary trap or inspection shaft.The invert of the outlet of the reflux valve shall be installed a minimum of 80mm higher than the invert of the <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1376_4.2.0.xml#_12d6153c-4986-4856-80c0-e21bb57af12f" id="_3ca02df4-19d7-4721-aa31-d23b6e5bedad" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="abcb-glossentry">Network Utility Operator</xref>’s system it is connected to. </p><p>NOTE 1: See NSW Figures C2D4a and C2D4b.</p><p>NOTE 2: Where a reflux valve is installed the valve remains the responsibility of the property owner.</p><p>(e) Clause 4.6.2 insert subclause: (d) be installed vertically with no offsets.</p><p>(f) Clause 4.6.7.1 insert the following as the second paragraph: A submerged floor waste gully and compact floor waste gully with water seal trap insert shall only be used in sanitary plumbing systems. </p><p>(g) Clause 4.7.1 insert subclauses (i) and (j): (i) At each drain connecting one or more water closets or slop hoppers to provide direct maintenance rodding access and be raised to finished surface level in an accessible location with a sealed airtight cover. If access to an under floor area is more than 600mm above the inspection opening, the riser may be omitted. (j) at the point to which a drain connects to an onsite wastewater treatment system, wet well or similar apparatuses. For wet wells and similar apparatuses with electrical components located within, a junction of 45° in the opposite direction of flow and vertical riser terminated at ground level with a sealed airtight cover shall be installed to direct future drain maintenance away from the wet well or apparatus.</p><p>NOTE: Water Closets and Slop Hoppers where connected to sanitary plumbing and above ground pipework using <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1249_0.8.0.xml#_25307451-c7e1-4167-b4de-e5a1af26694c" id="_10512c3a-e9b9-432b-b332-7ab1a9a5923d" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">drainage</xref> principles are not subject to the requirements of Clause 4.7.1 (i).</p><p>(h) Insert Clause 4.12 Flexible joints in drains where:</p><p>	(i) 4.12.1 - General: Flexible joints should be installed to accommodate movement to 	drains that may otherwise cause damage and affect the normal performance of a sanitary 	<xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1249_0.8.0.xml#_25307451-c7e1-4167-b4de-e5a1af26694c" id="_a6a48d48-6a5a-4c3a-b27a-40461363a334" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">drainage</xref> system.</p><p>NOTE: See PCA Variation Clause 5.6 for information on Drains in other than stable ground.</p><p>	(ii) 4.12.2 – Location: Where flexible joints are installed in a sanitary <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1249_0.8.0.xml#_25307451-c7e1-4167-b4de-e5a1af26694c" id="_7546d10a-5321-4012-86d3-85812267c6ea" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">drainage</xref> system to 	accommodate ground movement, a detailed design of the installation shall be prepared 	by a suitably qualified engineer or recognised expert for the sanitary <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1249_0.8.0.xml#_25307451-c7e1-4167-b4de-e5a1af26694c" id="_6cbad656-ce9e-46bc-840f-a1524a866419" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">drainage</xref> system to 	avoid damage from ground movement. The design shall include the proposed locations 	of the flexible joints and any alternative methods of support for the sanitary <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1249_0.8.0.xml#_25307451-c7e1-4167-b4de-e5a1af26694c" id="_74ec9928-32c0-4fc7-b2c1-2f9c2e9cec6f" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">drainage</xref> 	system. The flexible joints shall be installed in the location and configuration detailed in 	the design and a copy of the design showing the location of the flexible joints shall be 	provided to the local plumbing regulator prior to an inspection.</p><p>NOTE 1: See Appendix G for information on the installation of plastic pipe <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1249_0.8.0.xml#_25307451-c7e1-4167-b4de-e5a1af26694c" id="_7504140e-1150-4f7a-b886-cda68a4ea539" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">drainage</xref> systems in unstable soils within Australia.</p><p>NOTE 2: AS2870 provides special design considerations for drains associated with residential slab or footing systems on moderately, highly or extremely reactive soils</p><p>NOTE 3: See PCA NSW Variation Clause 5.6 for information on Drains in other than stable ground.</p><p>(i) Clause 5.6 delete and insert: If drains are to be laid in filled, unstable, water-charged ground or ground prone to movement, methods of support, bedding or accommodating movement, shall be designed to withstand and suit the ground conditions where sanitary <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1249_0.8.0.xml#_25307451-c7e1-4167-b4de-e5a1af26694c" id="_4e55f869-f484-41bf-b54d-7298ac0a67b1" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">drainage</xref> on sites with soils classified H1, H2 and E should accommodate ground movement.</p><p>NOTE 1: For proclaimed mine subsidence or landslip district the appropriate authority should be referred to for advice on subsidence or landslip design condition parameters for proposed <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1249_0.8.0.xml#_25307451-c7e1-4167-b4de-e5a1af26694c" id="_79d0c409-6c5c-40a1-b8fd-4bb093013800" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">drainage</xref> systems.</p><p>NOTE 2: Sites with soils classified M or P may be provided with protection from ground movement.</p><p>NOTE 3: Clause 3.8.3 provide special design considerations for drains in close proximity to footings.</p><p>NOTE 4: See PCA Variation Clause 4.12 for Flexible joints in drains requirements.</p><p>NOTE 5: See Appendix G for information on the installation of plastic pipe <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1249_0.8.0.xml#_25307451-c7e1-4167-b4de-e5a1af26694c" id="_4f69c62c-f399-4af0-a6ad-b4e79ea703c8" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">drainage</xref> systems in unstable soils within Australia.</p><p>NOTE 6: AS2870 provides special design considerations for drains associated with residential slab or footing systems on moderately, highly or extremely reactive soils.</p><p>NOTE 7: In Australia performance requirements are prescribed in the Plumbing Code of Australia to ensure that a design may be suitable. A performance solution is to be provided to the Plumbing Regulator.</p><p>(j) Clause 12.6.3 delete and insert: The wet well shall have a minimum DN 80 Vent except where:</p><p>	(i) manufactured wet wells are watermark approved with a smaller vent size; or</p><p>	(ii) the pump and wet well is approved for use by the <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1376_4.2.0.xml#_12d6153c-4986-4856-80c0-e21bb57af12f" id="_1ad1797a-bb2a-456d-9255-16000b8d8f4e" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="abcb-glossentry">Network Utility Operator</xref> of the 	pressure sewer system to which it will connect and has a self venting lid or similar.</p><p>	(iii) Venting of a wet well is not to cause nuisance to occupants of a dwelling.</p><p>(k) Clause 12.7 delete and insert: : The pump discharge pressure piping shall conform to the relevant sections of AS/NZS 3500.1 and this document. The outlet pipe shall discharge to one of the following locations:</p><p>	(i) An inspection chamber</p><p>	(ii) A boundary trap shaft</p><p>	(iii) A stack below the lowest fixture connection on any floor.</p><p>	(iv) A drain or combined discharge pipe, provided the connection is at least 2.5m form 	any other connection.</p><p>	(v) Downstream of a reflux valve or at least 2.5m upstream of a reflux valve.</p><p>	(vi) A minimum of 1m downstream of a boundary trap.</p><p>	(vii) Direct to the <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1376_4.2.0.xml#_12d6153c-4986-4856-80c0-e21bb57af12f" id="_74e77202-9849-4fce-8c9b-88a71682f3df" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="abcb-glossentry">Network Utility Operator</xref>’s sewer where approved by the <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1376_4.2.0.xml#_12d6153c-4986-4856-80c0-e21bb57af12f" id="_99ad3579-c49a-4c4c-a8f9-13acc0b705b6" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="abcb-glossentry">Network Utility 	Operator</xref>.</p><p>	(viii) A marker tape must be laid along the top of all pump discharge or rising mains pipes 	at intervals of not more than 3 m.</p><p>NOTE 1: Sewage management facilities shall be accredited by NSW Health and comply with local government requirements. </p><p>NOTE 2: Before a connection is made to pump raw sewage or effluent from a septic tank or holding well to the <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1376_4.2.0.xml#_12d6153c-4986-4856-80c0-e21bb57af12f" id="_3124bd5a-f9c1-4b82-be1b-7aac5b117b25" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="abcb-glossentry">Network Utility Operator</xref>’s sewer, an application must be made to that <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/1376_4.2.0.xml#_12d6153c-4986-4856-80c0-e21bb57af12f" id="_0343f6df-e857-491f-ba09-7669e546e444" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="abcb-glossentry">Network Utility Operator</xref>. Applicants must meet the pump to sewer requirements and conditions for all connections to the sewer. </p></subclause><image-reference conref="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/4252_0.4.0.xml" id="_5354bb05-80df-482a-bfab-c215b3833c84" variation="NSW"><num/><title id="_95885a49-530a-475a-a780-43fc52c46951"/></image-reference><image-reference conref="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/1c3f2f74-4ee1-4cdd-b1b4-53c91069d002/4253_0.3.0.xml" id="_5e199768-398e-4a48-b90a-cd0b6ca5a380" variation="NSW"><num/><title id="_e82595c3-5314-470c-b70e-053c64ef9524"/></image-reference><callout id="_ed9c89e4-2e0c-4703-be26-aa3eb2b8c283"><callout-type ncc-info-type="notes"/><p>Where a reflux valve is installed the valve remains the responsibility of the property owner.</p></callout></clause>