<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><table-reference xmlns:xt="urn:xpressauthor:trackchanges" graph="None" id="_e7476a5d-8f5e-4dc7-960d-0db7b2969ffc"><num>1</num><title id="_17cea58c-5df0-4a88-ac12-8645863c073e">List of amendments - NCC 2025 Volume Three</title><table id="_08b593c3-6759-4da9-b473-98f0506d772f" keycol="1"><tgroup cols="2"><colspec colname="001" colnum="1" colwidth="216.00*"/><colspec colname="002" colnum="2" colwidth="216.00*"/><thead><row><entry>Reference</entry><entry>Changes and commentary</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001">Section A—Governing requirements</entry></row><row><entry>A2G2</entry><entry>A new sub-clause added to specify that Performance Solutions for the structural reliability of components must be at least equivalent to solutions developed using the Deemed-to-Satisfy Provisions. A Note has been included to outline transitional arrangements.</entry></row><row><entry>A2G2</entry><entry>A limitations statement has been added that prohibits the use of A2G2(2)(c)—Expert Judgement—in Performance Solutions for certain Performance Requirements, to the extent these Performance Requirements relate to structural or fire safety.</entry></row><row><entry>A4G1</entry><entry>Multiple amendments, including new Notes and Exemptions, to permit the use of an edition of a document edition found on the register of alternative referenced documents as an alternative to the edition listed in Schedule 2.</entry></row><row><entry>A5G6(1) &amp; (3)</entry><entry>Multiple amendments to allow a building material, component or assembly to be deemed to have a fire hazard property where it differs in a minor degree to a tested prototype, as confirmed by an Accredited Testing Laboratory.</entry></row><row><entry>A5G6(2)</entry><entry>A new sub-clause has been added to specify methods for determining combustibility.</entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001">Part B1—Cold water services</entry></row><row><entry>B1P2</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>B1P3</entry><entry>Clarification amendments, including separation of isolation requirements into a new Performance Requirement, B1P4.</entry></row><row><entry>B1P4</entry><entry>Isolation requirements of B1P3 of NCC 2022 have been clarified and relocated to B1P4.</entry></row><row><entry>B1P5</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>B1P7</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>B1V1</entry><entry>A new Verification Method, Determination of velocity, has been inserted to provide an option for verification of compliance with B1P2.</entry></row><row><entry>B1D3(2)</entry><entry>A new sub-clause has been added to require that above-ground pipes and fittings in combined sprinkler and hydrant systems meet certain material requirements. </entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001">Part B2—Heated water services</entry></row><row><entry>B2P3</entry><entry>Clarification amendments. Also, updated flow velocity for non-copper circulatory systems.</entry></row><row><entry>B2P4</entry><entry>Clarification amendments, including separation of isolation requirements into a new Performance Requirement, B2P5.</entry></row><row><entry>B2P5</entry><entry>Isolation requirements of B2P4 of NCC 2022 have been clarified and relocated to B2P5.</entry></row><row><entry>B2P9</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>B2P11</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>B2D2</entry><entry>Minimum Small-scale Technology Certificates values have been updated. Also, a limitation has been introduced to allow compliance with relevant Volume Two provisions in lieu of B2D2 in certain circumstances.</entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001">Part B3—Non-drinking water services</entry></row><row><entry>B3P3</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>B3P4</entry><entry>Clarification amendments, including separation of isolation requirements into a new Performance Requirement, B3P5.</entry></row><row><entry>B3P5</entry><entry>Isolation requirements of B3P4 of NCC 2022 have been clarified and relocated to B3P5.</entry></row><row><entry>B3P7</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>B3P8</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001">Part B4—Fire-fighting water services</entry></row><row><entry>B4P1</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>B4P2</entry><entry>Clarification amendments, including separation of isolation requirements into a new Performance Requirement, B4P3.</entry></row><row><entry>B4P3</entry><entry>Isolation requirements of B4P2 of NCC 2022 have been clarified and relocated to B4P3.</entry></row><row><entry>B4P4</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>B4D3(3)</entry><entry>A new sub-clause has been added to require that above-ground pipes and fittings in combined sprinkler and hydrant systems meet certain material requirements. Part B5—Cross-connection control</entry></row><row><entry>B5V1(2)</entry><entry>The circumstances that represent a hazard have been updated.</entry></row><row><entry>B5V1(3)</entry><entry>Amended to include general reference to AS/NZS 3500.1.</entry></row><row><entry>B5D3</entry><entry>The circumstances that represent a hazard have been updated. Amended to include general reference to AS/NZS 3500.1. A new exemption has been included for independent, non-drinking water services used for agriculture.</entry></row><row><entry>B5D4(b)</entry><entry>Amended to include general reference to AS/NZS 3500.1.</entry></row><row><entry>B5D7</entry><entry>Cross-connection hazard provisions contained in Specification 41 of NCC 2022 have been relocated to a new clause, B5D7.</entry></row><row><entry>Specification 41</entry><entry>The requirements of Specification 41 of NCC 2022 have been relocated to B5D7.</entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001">Part B6—Rainwater services</entry></row><row><entry>B6P2</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>B6P3</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>B6P4</entry><entry>Clarification amendments, including separation of isolation requirements into a new Performance Requirement, B6P5.</entry></row><row><entry>B6P5</entry><entry>Isolation requirements of B6P4 of NCC 2022 have been clarified and relocated to B6P5.</entry></row><row><entry>B6P7</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>B6D3</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>B6D5</entry><entry>Isolation requirements of B6D5 of NCC 2022 have been relocated to B6D6.</entry></row><row><entry>B6D6</entry><entry>New provision for isolation created as a consequence of removing isolation requirements from B6D5 of NCC 2022.</entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001">Part B7—Rainwater storage</entry></row><row><entry>B7P1</entry><entry>Clarification amendments. Inclusion of exemption for sites not connected to a Network Utility Operator drinking water supply.</entry></row><row><entry>B7P2</entry><entry>Clarification amendments. Inclusion of exemption for sites not connected to a Network Utility Operator drinking water supply.</entry></row><row><entry>B7P3</entry><entry>Clarification amendments, including separation of isolation requirements into a new Performance Requirement, B7P4. Inclusion of exemption for sites not connected to a Network Utility Operator drinking water supply.</entry></row><row><entry>B7P4</entry><entry>Isolation requirements of B7P3 of NCC 2022 have been clarified and relocated to B7P4. Inclusion of exemption for sites not connected to a Network Utility Operator drinking water supply.</entry></row><row><entry>B7P5</entry><entry>Inclusion of exemption for sites not connected to a Network Utility Operator drinking water supply.</entry></row><row><entry>B7D2</entry><entry>An application provision is included to provide exemption for sites not connected to a Network Utility Operator drinking water supply.</entry></row><row><entry>B7D3</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001">Part C1—Sanitary plumbing systems</entry></row><row><entry>C1P1</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>C1P2</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>C1P4</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>C1P6</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>C1P7</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>Table C1V1a and Table C1V1b</entry><entry>Frequency factors and discharge unit values have been updated.</entry></row><row><entry>C1V2</entry><entry>Verification Methods C1V2 of C1V5 of NCC 2022 for pipe sizing have been replaced with a new Verification Method, C1V2.</entry></row><row><entry>C1V3</entry><entry>C1V3 of NCC 2022 has been deleted.</entry></row><row><entry>C1V4</entry><entry>C1V4 of NCC 2022 has been deleted.</entry></row><row><entry>C1V5</entry><entry>C1V5 of NCC 2022 has been deleted.</entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001">Part C2—Sanitary drainage systems

</entry></row><row><entry>C2P1</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>C2P2</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>C2P3</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>C2P5</entry><entry>Clarification amendments and incorporation of quantified requirements for trap seals.</entry></row><row><entry>C2P6</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>C2P7</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>C2V2</entry><entry>Amended to include general reference to AS/NZS 3500.2.</entry></row><row><entry>C2V3</entry><entry>Frequency factors and discharge unit values have been updated.</entry></row><row><entry>C2V4</entry><entry>A new Verification Method, Sanitary drainage design, has been included as an option to verify compliance with C2P1.</entry></row><row><entry>C2D3</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001">Schedule 1—Definitions</entry></row><row><entry>Abbreviations</entry><entry>Diameter Nominal (DN) has been added to Abbreviations.</entry></row><row><entry>Symbols</entry><entry>Carbon dioxide equivalent per square metre hour (CO<sub id="_402a2450-41b1-476c-ab03-0051a72008cd">2</sub>-e/m<sup id="_352a8e95-c253-468d-8624-6a08c902ae15">2</sup>.hr) has been added to Symbols.</entry></row><row><entry>Symbols</entry><entry>Watt peak per meter squared output of a solar photovoltaic panel (Wp/m2) has been added to Symbols.</entry></row><row><entry>Allotment</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘allotment’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Ancillary components</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘ancillary components’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Cavity</entry><entry>The defined term ‘cavity’ has been amended to cover additional wall types.</entry></row><row><entry>Climate specific part load value</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘climate specific part load value’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Figure 2</entry><entry>Figure 2 has been updated.</entry></row><row><entry>Collected</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘collected’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Combustible</entry><entry>The defined term ‘combustible’ has been amended to require that determination using AS 1530.1 is to be undertaken by an Accredited Testing Laboratory. A transition period has been included for this amendment.</entry></row><row><entry>Condensation</entry><entry>The defined term ‘condensation’ has been amended to replace ‘moisture’ with ‘liquid water’.</entry></row><row><entry>Control layer</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘control layer’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Critical radiant flux</entry><entry>The defined term ‘critical radiant flux’ has been amended to require that determination using AS ISO 9239.1 is to be undertaken by an Accredited Testing Laboratory. A transition period has been included for this amendment.</entry></row><row><entry>Table 4</entry><entry>Amended to reflect updated wind classes B1 and B2.</entry></row><row><entry>Drainage system</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘drainage system’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Drained</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘drained’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Embodied carbon emissions</entry><entry>A defined term, ‘embodied carbon emissions’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Envelope</entry><entry>The defined term ‘envelope’ has been amended.</entry></row><row><entry>Fire hazard properties</entry><entry>The defined term ‘fire hazard properties’ has been amended to align methods of determination.</entry></row><row><entry>Fire protected steel</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘fire-protected steel’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Fire-source feature</entry><entry>The defined term ‘fire-source feature’ has been amended to include the construction edge or perimeter of another building on the allotment, which is not a Class 10 building, which has a use that constitutes a fire load.</entry></row><row><entry>Flammability index</entry><entry>The defined term ‘flammability Index’ has been amended to require that determination using AS 1530.2 is to be made by an Accredited Testing Laboratory. A transition period until the adoption of the next edition of the NCC has been included for this amendment.</entry></row><row><entry>House energy rating software</entry><entry>The defined term ‘house energy rating software’ has been amended to include reference to relevant Volume One provisions.</entry></row><row><entry>Kerb ramp</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘kerb ramp’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Mezzanine</entry><entry>The defined term ‘mezzanine’ has been amended for clarity.</entry></row><row><entry>NABERS Embodied Carbon</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘NABERS Embodied Carbon’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Non-combustible</entry><entry>The defined term ‘non-combustible’ has been amended to require that determination using AS 1530.1 is to be made by an Accredited Testing Laboratory. A transition period has been included for this amendment.</entry></row><row><entry>Occupiable outdoor area</entry><entry>Explanatory information has been provided to assist with interpretation.</entry></row><row><entry>Point of connection</entry><entry>The defined term, ‘Point of connection’, has been amended to incorporate rainwater storage.</entry></row><row><entry>Rainwater</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘rainwater’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Redirected</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘redirected’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Rising damp</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘rising damp’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Self-draining</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘self-draining’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Small sized, low-speed automatic lift</entry><entry>The defined term ‘small sized, low-speed automatic lift’ has been deleted.</entry></row><row><entry>Smoke-Developed Index</entry><entry>The defined term ‘Smoke-Developed Index’ has been amended to require that determination using AS/NZS 1530.3 is to be made by an Accredited Testing Laboratory. A transition period until the adoption of the next edition of the NCC has been included for this amendment.</entry></row><row><entry>Smoke development rate</entry><entry>The defined term ‘smoke development rate’ has been amended to require that determination using AS ISO 9239.1 is to be made by an Accredited Testing Laboratory. A transition period has been included for this amendment.</entry></row><row><entry>Solar Reflectance Index</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘Solar Reflectance Index’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Spread-of-Flame Index</entry><entry>The defined term ‘Spread-of-Flame Index’ has been amended to require that determination using AS 1530.3 is to be made by an Accredited Testing Laboratory. A transition period has been included for this amendment.</entry></row><row><entry>Step ramp</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘step ramp’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Stormwater</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘stormwater’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Structural substrate</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘structural substrate’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Sub-surface water</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘sub-surface water’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Surface finish</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘surface finish’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Surface water</entry><entry>The defined term ‘surface water’ has been amended for clarity.</entry></row><row><entry>Surface water seepage</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘surface water seepage’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Threshold ramp</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘threshold ramp’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Total Solar Reflectance</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘Total Solar Reflectance (TSR)’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Upfront embodied carbon</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘upfront embodied carbon’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Water</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘water’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Water services overflow</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘water services overflow’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001">Schedule 2—Referenced documents

</entry></row><row><entry>AS ISO 717 Part 1</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS ISO 717 Part 1 ‘Acoustics — Rating of sound insulation in buildings and of building elements — Airborne sound insulation’ has been referenced. The associated note (Note 1) has been updated accordingly.</entry></row><row><entry>AS ISO 717 Part 2</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS ISO 717 Part 2 ‘Acoustics — Rating of sound insulation in buildings and of building elements — Impact sound insulation’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS 1170 Part 2</entry><entry>Amdts 1 and 2 of the 2021 edition of AS/NZS 1170 Part 2 ‘Structural design actions — Wind actions’ have been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1170 Part 4</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS 1170 Part 4 ‘Structural design actions — Earthquake actions in Australia’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1530 Part 1</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS/NZS 1530 Part 1 ‘Methods for fire tests on building materials, components and structures — Combustibility test for materials (ISO 1182:2020, NEQ)’ has been referenced. A note concerning existing tests (Note 2) has been incorporated accordingly.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1530 Part 8.1</entry><entry>Amdt 1 of the 2018 edition of AS 1530 Part 8.1 ‘Methods for fire tests on building materials, components and structures — Tests on elements of construction for buildings exposed to simulated bushfire attack — Radiant heat and small flaming sources’ has been referenced. A note concerning existing tests (Note 3) has been incorporated accordingly.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1668 Part 2</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS 1668 Part 2 ‘The use of ventilation and air conditioning in buildings — Mechanical ventilation in buildings’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1668 Part 4</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS 1668 Part 4 ‘The use of ventilation and air conditioning in buildings — Natural ventilation of buildings’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1670 Part 1</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS 1670 Part 1 ‘Fire detection, warning, control and intercom systems — System design, installation and commissioning — Fire’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1670 Part 3</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS 1670 Part 3 ‘Fire detection, warning, control and intercom systems — System design, installation and commissioning — Fire alarm monitoring’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1670 Part 4</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS 1670 Part 4 ‘Fire detection, warning, control and intercom systems — System design, installation and commissioning — Emergency warning and intercom systems’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1684 Part 2</entry><entry>Amdt 1 of the 2021 edition of AS 1684 Part 2 ‘Residential timber-framed construction — Non-cyclonic areas’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1684 Part 3</entry><entry>Amdt 1 of the 2021 edition of AS 1684 Part 3 ‘Residential timber-framed construction — Cyclonic areas’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1684 Part 4</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS 1684 Part 4 ‘Residential timber-framed construction — Simplified — Non-cyclonic areas’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1926 Part 1</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS 1926 Part 1 ‘Swimming pool safety — Safety barriers for swimming pools’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 2118 Part 6</entry><entry>The 2026 edition of AS 2118 Part 6 ‘Automatic fire sprinkler systems — Combined sprinkler and hydrant systems in multistorey buildings’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 2200</entry><entry>The 2006 edition of AS 2200 ‘Design charts for water supply and sewerage (incorporating amendment 1)’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS 3500 Part 1</entry><entry>The 2025 edition of AS/NZS 3500 Part 1 ‘Plumbing and drainage — Water services’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS 3500 Part 2</entry><entry>The 2025 edition of AS/NZS 3500 Part 2 ‘Plumbing and drainage — Sanitary plumbing and drainage’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS 3500 Part 3</entry><entry>The 2025 edition of AS/NZS 3500 Part 3 ‘Plumbing and drainage — Stormwater drainage’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS 3500 Part 4</entry><entry>The 2025 edition of AS/NZS 3500 Part 4 ‘Plumbing and drainage — Heated water services’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 3786</entry><entry>The 2023 edition of AS 3786 ‘Smoke alarms using scattered light, transmitted light or ionization’ has been referenced. The note regarding existing tests (Note 7) has been updated accordingly.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS 4020</entry><entry>Amdt 1 of the 2018 edition of AS/NZS 4020 ‘Testing of products for use in contact with drinking water’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 4055</entry><entry>Amdt 1 of the 2021 edition of AS 4055 ‘Wind loads for housing’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS 4859 Part 1</entry><entry>Amdt 1 of the 2018 edition of AS/NZS 4859 Part 1 ‘Thermal insulation materials for buildings — General criteria and technical provisions’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 5346</entry><entry>The 2023 edition of AS 5346 ‘Exterior insulation and finish cladding systems’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS 5601 Part 1</entry><entry>The 2022 edition of AS/NZS 5601 Part 1 ‘Gas installations — General installations (incorporating amendments 1 and 2)’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS ISO 5151</entry><entry>The 2023 edition of AS/NZS ISO 5151 ‘Non-ducted air conditioners and heat pumps — Testing and rating for performance’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS ISO 13256.1</entry><entry>The 2023 edition of AS/NZS ISO 13256.1 ‘Water source heat pumps — Testing and rating for performance — Water-to-air and brine-to-air heat pumps’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>ASTM-E1980-11</entry><entry>The 2019 edition of ASTM-E1980-11 ‘Standard Practice for Calculating Solar Reflectance Index of Horizontal and Low Sloped Opaque Surfaces’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>EN14511-2</entry><entry>The 2022 edition of EN14511-2 ‘Air-conditioners, liquid chilling packages and heat pumps for space heating and cooling and process chillers, with electricity driven compressors — Test conditions’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>EN14825</entry><entry>The 2022 edition of EN14825 ‘Air conditioners, liquid chilling packages and heat pumps, with electrically driven compressors, for space heating and cooling, commercial and process cooling — Testing and rating at part load conditions and calculation of seasonal performance’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>NSF/ANSI/CAN 372</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of NSF/ANSI/CAN 372 ‘Drinking Water System Components — Lead Content’ has been referenced. A note regarding existing tests (Note 10) has been incorporated.</entry></row><row><entry>SA TS 5367</entry><entry>The 2021 edition of SA TS 5367 ‘Photoluminescent exit signage — Product specification, installation and operation’ has been referenced.</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></table-reference>