<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?Xpress productLine="ncc-clause" ?><clause xmlns:xt="urn:xpressauthor:trackchanges" id="_032874ef-808f-49cc-9509-3f66e6222bae" outputclass="ncc-clause"><meta><facet building="Class 2"/><facet building="Class 3"/><facet building="Class 4"/><facet building="Class 5"/><facet building="Class 6"/><facet building="Class 7a"/><facet building="Class 7b"/><facet building="Class 8"/><facet building="Class 9a"/><facet building="Class 9b"/><facet building="Class 9c"/><facet building="Class 10b"/><facet building="Class 10c"/></meta><sptc>H7D5</sptc><title id="_e98fb018-4398-4783-b8b8-e8797053bc7c">Heating appliances, fireplaces, chimneys and flues</title><archive-num>2019: 3.10.7</archive-num><subclause id="_8ebf78ba-581e-40e6-b952-66e03a25e923" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_4855afce-90d5-402e-8ab8-aa377cb14643">SubClause</title><num>1</num><p><xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/8bd50c59-637c-4a79-8565-09cd674ed7ed/1395_4.0.0.xml#_f7304862-3529-49d7-9f62-352bcbcb6294" id="_ec7240ed-b17f-47ff-97a0-46f0d1f64c0e" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">Performance Requirement</xref> <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/8bd50c59-637c-4a79-8565-09cd674ed7ed/1977_3.6.0.xml#_01ac9637-167b-4e89-b0dd-6843aa3c6d5c" id="_06f25404-56d5-4241-8670-b194990c735d" scope="local" type="clause">H7P3</xref> is satisfied for a heating appliance if it is installed in accordance with—</p><ol outputclass="alpha"><li id="_84de02cb-0030-4a89-802e-2377aafa6c13">for a domestic solid fuel burning appliance, AS/NZS 2918; or </li><li id="_0de081c1-11e1-4d36-b28d-ca5677f53640">for a heating appliance, <xref format="dita" href="qpp://assets/4230#_99ae28ad-343e-4437-8c1c-0cf518f9c6bd" id="_ee6fae44-98c0-4a3c-ade9-0df18c924334" publishing-id="housing" scope="external" type="part">Part 12.4</xref> of the ABCB Housing Provisions.</li></ol></subclause><callout id="_6b28729b-f32f-4d74-9729-32e9f986f9c6"><callout-type ncc-info-type="info"/><p>H7D5 applies to three types of heating appliances and includes the following:</p><ul outputclass="numbered"><li>Open fireplaces — where solid fuel such as timber or coals are burnt in an unenclosed compartment. The requirements in <xref format="dita" href="qpp://assets/4230#_99ae28ad-343e-4437-8c1c-0cf518f9c6bd" id="_4104edf8-f711-4c9c-bcc8-d0d7f8f9baa5" publishing-id="housing" referencetype="Text" scope="external" synctargettext="false" type="standard-part">Part 12.4</xref> of the ABCB Housing Provisions for open fireplaces relate to masonry or concrete construction for all parts including the hearth, external faces and walls forming the back and sides and chimney.</li><li>Insert fireplaces — manufactured and assembled in factories and inserted into the openings of masonry fireplaces in a building. All insert fireplaces must be tested to AS/NZS 2918 and have closed fire compartments for the burning of solid fuels.</li><li>Free standing heating appliances — manufactured and assembled in factories and installed in the building without being concealed by wall or floor elements. All free standing fireplaces must be tested to AS/NZS 2918 and are <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/8bd50c59-637c-4a79-8565-09cd674ed7ed/1432_4.0.0.xml#_af6fde9f-147d-4782-8b85-42044e80fd42" id="_7f617d3f-0c4b-47de-8263-5fd7f230f184" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="abcb-glossentry">required</xref> to be positioned in a building that meets specific minimum distances from internal building elements.</li></ul><p>The requirements of both H7D5(a) and <xref format="dita" href="qpp://assets/4230#_99ae28ad-343e-4437-8c1c-0cf518f9c6bd" id="_e3ef37e3-3373-4295-95dd-fa4e20310f6e" publishing-id="housing" referencetype="Text" scope="external" synctargettext="false" type="standard-part">Part 12.4</xref> of the ABCB Housing Provisions are intended to ensure the construction or installation of heating appliances can withstand the temperatures they generate. The requirements also ensure there is no spread of fire from within the heating appliance to adjacent building elements.</p><p>In addition to this, the requirements ensure hot products of combustion and smoke do not affect the occupants within the building. This is achieved by requiring construction and installation of heating appliances to transfer products of combustion and smoke directly to the outside atmosphere.</p><p>Insert fireplaces fuelled by gas are not covered by <xref format="dita" href="qpp://assets/4230#_99ae28ad-343e-4437-8c1c-0cf518f9c6bd" id="_2b31c220-ef6c-4035-8ebd-dcc352004c6e" publishing-id="housing" referencetype="Text" scope="external" synctargettext="false" type="standard-part">Part 12.4</xref> of the ABCB Housing Provisions. Insert gas fireplaces may be regulated by relevant authorities responsible for gas installations in each State or Territory jurisdiction and may be required to comply with AS/NZS 5601 – Gas installations.</p></callout></clause>