<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?Xpress productLine="ncc-clause" ?><clause xmlns:xt="urn:xpressauthor:trackchanges" id="_36d678f1-4c47-4c09-a0a9-b67afb8d00dc" outputclass="ncc-clause"><meta><facet building="Class 2"/><facet building="Class 3"/><facet building="Class 4"/><facet building="Class 5"/><facet building="Class 6"/><facet building="Class 7a"/><facet building="Class 7b"/><facet building="Class 8"/><facet building="Class 9a"/><facet building="Class 9b"/><facet building="Class 9c"/><facet building="Class 10b"/><facet building="Class 10c"/></meta><sptc>H7V1</sptc><title id="_85eee45f-e494-4902-baea-2d7511d793f4">Combustion appliances</title><archive-num>2019: V2.7.1</archive-num><subclause id="_9c733317-6d36-4a3b-b170-003559f29c61" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_0a156beb-f0da-49a0-a871-6efd93f100be">SubClause</title><num>1</num><p>Compliance with <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/8bd50c59-637c-4a79-8565-09cd674ed7ed/1977_3.6.0.xml#_01ac9637-167b-4e89-b0dd-6843aa3c6d5c" id="_d4dc8664-37f8-4ace-b21c-dcd24b6dbdef" scope="local" type="clause">H7P3(a)</xref> and <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/8bd50c59-637c-4a79-8565-09cd674ed7ed/1977_3.6.0.xml#_01ac9637-167b-4e89-b0dd-6843aa3c6d5c" id="_82d0731b-6f91-4cbe-85c9-57180f44cd2c" scope="local" type="clause">(b)</xref> is verified when—</p><ol outputclass="alpha"><li id="_3b645bd3-8de0-49c9-bb99-83c24e9dcdf0">components used within an appliance and its installation are constructed from—<ol><li>heat-resistant materials for maximum operating temperatures more than 600℃, where the material complies with (c); or</li><li>heat-tolerant materials for maximum operating temperatures more than 150℃ and less than 600℃, where the material complies with (c); and</li></ol></li><li id="_19548acb-e6b0-4fa3-834a-85d24a68ccf0">the building elements surrounding the appliance maintain their designed function and material properties inclusive of a full range of thermal movements when exposed to the heat effects of the appliance; and</li><li id="_b9e5a7d1-6037-4cfb-a9a8-0e11750335ba">a sample of the material is tested to the maximum operating temperature, specified in (a)(i) or (a)(ii) for a minimum of 96 hours; and </li><li id="_0d127f76-bc30-4795-8dd6-067e168d9f50">the tested sample, when allowed to cool, must be free from—<ol><li>visible cracks and fractures; and</li><li>visible indication of de-lamination; and</li><li>linear distortion in excess of the equivalent of 10 mm per metre, and</li><li>deterioration of the appearance of any surface finish, when compared to an unheated sample.</li></ol></li></ol></subclause><callout id="_a9bfb7d1-5570-4a49-8042-bde9e5636dae"><callout-type ncc-info-type="info"/><p>Under H7V1, it needs to be demonstrated that the proposed appliance will not deteriorate under standard operating conditions. Examples of deterioration may include deformation or failure of components that would render the appliance unsafe to use.</p><p>For the purposes of demonstrating compliance with (a), the typical operating temperature of a combustion device can be established by testing.</p><p>For the purposes of demonstrating compliance with (b), materials used for building elements (walls, floors and ceiling) in the areas surrounding an appliance can be appropriately selected and/or designed to align with the quantified values as determined by (a). This could either be achieved by using <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/8bd50c59-637c-4a79-8565-09cd674ed7ed/1264_2.2.0.xml#_1913e927-f74b-4892-bfc1-18eb299f184b" id="_610b0785-417b-4c95-9d0b-93b6cdeb0b31" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">Expert Judgement</xref> or by adhering to manufacturer's specifications. Certification in accordance with CodeMark Australia would also be a possibility in demonstrating compliance using the <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/8bd50c59-637c-4a79-8565-09cd674ed7ed/1506_27.0.0.xml#_a953dcf6-ebab-404f-a3f1-6d85f87ab898" id="_f24c10bf-19f6-495d-87ea-2ba45c2e7a52" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">Verification Method</xref>.</p><p>Full range of thermal movements relates to both the appliance and materials when exposed to both the heated and ambient conditions.</p><p>Benefits to industry derived from the application of this <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/8bd50c59-637c-4a79-8565-09cd674ed7ed/1506_27.0.0.xml#_a953dcf6-ebab-404f-a3f1-6d85f87ab898" id="_3f7bcb91-d7dd-4ac5-b5fc-5d8e6fb9cae7" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">Verification Method</xref> includes the potential use of non-standard national or internationally manufactured appliances. For example, test reports from appliances complying with various ISO Standards and various British Standards could be used to demonstrate compliance with the <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/8bd50c59-637c-4a79-8565-09cd674ed7ed/1506_27.0.0.xml#_a953dcf6-ebab-404f-a3f1-6d85f87ab898" id="_a9d98ce9-2e9a-446c-89cc-5814d387d379" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">Verification Method</xref>. The <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/8bd50c59-637c-4a79-8565-09cd674ed7ed/1506_27.0.0.xml#_a953dcf6-ebab-404f-a3f1-6d85f87ab898" id="_b3d8641d-1faf-4d96-9793-08224358e5d4" scope="local" type="abcb-glossentry">Verification Method</xref> also allows for in situ testing of unique combustion appliances, which would not easily be tested in accordance with the Australian Standard. Such testing would need to be verified by a suitably qualified practitioner and be supported by appropriate documentation.</p></callout></clause>