<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?Xpress productLine="page" ?><page xmlns:qxa="true" xmlns:xt="urn:xpressauthor:trackchanges" id="_40fde0fc-dd58-483e-82fa-cbd9a2af8cd3" outputclass="page"><title id="_5cbcd36c-aa52-4fda-91d0-a7e4c68cc2de">History of Adoption - NCC Volume Two</title><section id="_4bd8b4fc-6f6c-42a4-ad3e-b71053dca66e"><title id="_63738a43-1c0c-47a0-bb9e-304529e8590b">Adoption of NCC Volume Two</title><p>The adoption of each edition of NCC Volume Two (also referred to as BCA Volume Two) is set out in Table 1.</p><table-reference conref="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/8bd50c59-637c-4a79-8565-09cd674ed7ed/1630_0.25.0.xml" graph="None" id="_77458ba6-1904-4f31-833d-48d2959a1561"><num/><title id="_aabcf0ff-af1b-4c9d-a090-8f251ced4b04"/></table-reference></section><section id="_72453fe3-ca0d-4221-a512-7c9c3a0d1816"><title id="_6fd11f04-3065-4010-aa87-23a451d3af8c">Adoption of BCA 96 Volume Two</title><p>The 1996 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p></section><section id="_277b4582-2c72-4eca-8755-c24d398b9fa7"><title id="_c616bcd5-c12e-4dd4-8441-c9505f9a3186">BCA 96 Amendment No. 1</title><p>Amendment No. 1 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of Amendment No. 1 is to—</p><ul><li>include typographical changes including spelling, punctuation, cross references and layout; and</li><li>include reference to a Certificate of Conformity issued by the ABCB in A2.2; and</li><li>change the reference to the Standards Mark Certificate to refer to JAS–ANZ in A2.2; and</li><li>update references to Standards.</li></ul><p>Note: The revisions contained in Amendment No. 1 to the Housing Provisions have not been marked in the text.</p></section><section id="_fde92ed6-ced7-4f4d-973c-f3a05121c90e"><title id="_00cb4c10-5918-4d14-b38a-3543f971d1c1">BCA 96 Amendment No. 2</title><p>Amendment No. 2 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of Amendment No. 2 is to—</p><ul><li>include typographical changes including spelling, punctuation, cross references and layout; and</li><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_360a53d8-a25a-402f-a912-7b6d4e01deac"><title id="_9e599f81-4b67-45a9-af75-058794acf63d">BCA 96 Amendment No. 3</title><p>Amendment No. 3 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of Amendment No. 3 is to—</p><ul><li>incorporate the outcomes of the 1997 ABCB Variations Conference; and</li><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_3c8ad891-7e31-4ebe-bcf3-a35498a78e34"><title id="_cf476627-8984-4394-a262-ba6f51b8800e">BCA 96 Amendment No. 4</title><p>Amendment No. 4 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of Amendment No. 4 is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_88225de5-525d-4d0a-ad7e-06d3ed8c22d3"><title id="_f53cf144-ba83-40c6-a7fb-6f383301abb6">BCA 96 Amendment No. 5</title><p>Amendment No. 5 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of Amendment No. 5 is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>expand on the requirements for subfloor ventilation based on climatic conditions; and</li><li>revise the Acceptable Construction Practice for Steel framing; and</li><li>include additional details in the Acceptable Construction Practice for fencing of swimming pools; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_a1fb94b6-16be-4cb9-bb4f-c39d9ee1334c"><title id="_be1a2481-562e-4a39-8570-0e4501dd0966">BCA 96 Amendment No. 6</title><p>Amendment No. 6 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of Amendment No. 6 is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>revise the Acceptable Construction Practice for Footing and Slab Construction; and</li><li>replace Sound Transmission Class (STC) with weighted sound reduction index (R<sub id="_5787ee4b-7f6d-437e-aafc-4ebd3b78e6b2">w</sub>) within Part 3.8.6; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_b5d7a5e3-331b-4e23-b138-754f65853b09"><title id="_07ec0452-acb4-4a01-8874-55f8f7f04bc7">BCA 96 Amendment No. 7</title><p>Amendment No. 7 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of Amendment No. 7 is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>include requirements for separation of eaves and verandah spaces that are open to the roof space and common to 2 or more Class 1 buildings; and</li><li>reinstate the Acceptable Construction Practice for buildings in bushfire-prone areas, following alignment with the 1999 version of AS 3959; and</li><li>change the limitations on winders used in lieu of quarter and half landings within stairways; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_be6c0b08-50bd-4862-bdcd-34a6674cddc6"><title id="_4f51bb8a-2a2d-4bce-9934-721bdedfd245">BCA 96 Amendment No. 8</title><p>Amendment No. 8 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of Amendment No. 8 is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>include minor technical changes; and</li><li>achieve greater consistency between both Volumes of the BCA for stair construction.</li></ul></section><section id="_23dadcab-ccfd-49cb-bd17-550f7c5f6fd4"><title id="_7f0e3ede-dd92-4662-873d-ac65590eabf9">BCA 96 Amendment No. 9</title><p>Amendment No. 9 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of Amendment No. 9 is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>include minor technical changes; and</li><li>clarify which glazing assemblies must comply with AS 2047 and which must comply with AS 1288.</li></ul></section><section id="_f58e6dd2-8940-431f-8585-514073b692a7"><title id="_1beab9cc-b4b4-4ea1-bc18-a1a874d47cd0">BCA 96 Amendment No. 10</title><p>Amendment No. 10 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of Amendment No. 10 is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>update the requirements for protective coatings for steelwork in locations near saltwater; and</li><li>align Figure 3.6.1 dealing with glazing with AS 1288; and</li><li>extend the concession for fire separation of windows in non-habitable rooms to windows in bathrooms, laundries and toilets and also include buildings on the same allotment; and</li><li>replace testing to AS/NZS 1530.3 for timber in bushfire areas with reference to AS/NZS 3837; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_683ab6dd-a87b-435e-991c-881d6d3279ff"><title id="_2997a508-8f41-4b9d-bdc6-22585a030971">BCA 96 Amendment No. 11</title><p>Amendment No. 11 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of Amendment No. 11 is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>transfer public policy matters, with respect to structural adequacy, from the AS 1170 series to the BCA; and</li><li>introduce new definitions and more detailed provisions on the installation of flashings and damp-proof courses; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_77b4aad1-778a-452e-8460-176f43df94f9"><title id="_30881fb3-e674-42c3-8e2c-31a32742d12c">BCA 96 Amendment No. 12</title><p>Amendment No. 12 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of Amendment No. 12 is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>allow the use of either the 1989 editions or the 2002 editions of the 1170 series of standards; and</li><li>include Energy Efficiency measures into the Housing Provisions; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul><p> Note: Only substantive typographical corrections are noted in the margin.</p></section><section id="_33115926-8a48-4be7-b3b1-badaf2b1fb58"><title id="_449201bf-1299-4ff4-8ac7-9ad90ea95e63">BCA 96 Amendment No. 13</title><p>Amendment No. 13 of the 1996 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of Amendment No. 13 is to—</p><ul><li>update references to Standards; and</li><li>refine the Energy Efficiency provisions and advise of their adoption in Western Australia and Queensland; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul><p> Note: Only substantive typographical corrections are noted in the margin.</p></section><section id="_47d4bba0-f277-4b17-bd41-857a78b67d6f"><title id="_6b4a6d36-44da-4208-9641-6169fc0b49a0">Adoption of BCA 2004 Volume Two</title><p>The 2004 edition of the BCA was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of BCA 2004 Volume Two is to—</p><ul><li>remove references to BCA 96; and</li><li>clarify the method of determining the Performance Requirements that are relevant to Alternative Solutions; and</li><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>revise the acceptable construction practice for footing and slab construction; and</li><li>prohibit the use of lead on roofs used to collect potable water; and</li><li>reform the provisions for sound insulation; and</li><li>update the Energy Efficiency provisions; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_429d1ddc-373c-425e-99de-7af50082b1d3"><title id="_2cd125b0-fa43-4217-9d6e-0e1202a62460">Adoption of BCA 2005 Volume Two</title><p>The 2005 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of BCA 2005 Volume Two is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>update the provisions for waterproofing of wet areas; and</li><li>update balustrading provisions to include wire balustrades; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_3d6f806b-2983-418c-90c3-2a5f9d7b4833"><title id="_60f61ba2-4093-42fe-bcee-f3a074499a60">Adoption of BCA 2006 Volume Two</title><p>The 2006 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of BCA 2006 Volume Two is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>convert the W wind speed categories to the N and C wind speed categories; and</li><li>include a national testing regime for cladding in cyclonic areas; and</li><li>include enhanced energy efficiency provisions; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_2fcc4057-1e0b-474c-9531-1d8362f1ce29"><title id="_dac59020-5341-4baa-8fb0-af335ab3ca22">Adoption of BCA 2007 Volume Two</title><p>The 2007 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of BCA 2007 Volume Two is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>clarify that compliance with either the appropriate acceptable construction manuals or the appropriate acceptable construction practice set out in Section 3 is deemed to comply with the Performance Requirements; and</li><li>clarify when it is appropriate to use the acceptable construction practice for the installation of glazing and when it is necessary for windows to comply with AS 2047; and</li><li>update acceptable construction practice for the installation of glazing to align with recent changes to AS 1288; and</li><li>update Energy Efficiency provisions including providing clarification and additional information; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_5d93672a-275c-4039-92ec-f0201d83fb91"><title id="_4c8a8c92-52f2-445c-84a6-8ee470872597">Adoption of BCA 2008 Volume Two</title><p>The 2008 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of BCA 2008 Volume Two is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>include lists of other legislation affecting buildings in the various States and Territories; and</li><li>include provisions for swimming pool water recirculation systems; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_702c57b1-26b5-47b0-8b4c-033f244fe6b5"><title id="_5e7ec35d-1860-4d88-b957-dbb0ea3f3e54">Adoption of BCA 2009 Volume Two</title><p>The 2009 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of BCA 2009 Volume Two is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>after expiry of the agreed transition period, except for the 1993 edition of AS 1170.4, delete all references to the older loading standards contained in the AS 1170 series and consequently, all provisions referring to them; and</li><li>simplify the wire balustrade provisions including the addition of a Verification Method; and</li><li>clarify the height of rooms in an attic and with a sloping ceiling; and</li><li>clarify the provisions for the construction of sanitary compartments to enable an unconscious occupant to be removed; and</li><li>further update the energy efficiency provisions; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_3773b371-d94b-4f78-bfa3-2e2c85a9add2"><title id="_791cc9df-66b9-4ef9-ab11-9353f698b828">Adoption of BCA 2010 Volume Two</title><p>The 2010 edition of the BCA Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of BCA 2010 Volume Two is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>delete reference to the 1993 edition of AS 1170.4 and consequently all provisions referring to it; and</li><li>increase the stringency of the energy efficiency provisions and, as part of reducing greenhouse gas emissions, introduce provisions for lighting and the greenhouse gas intensity of the energy source for services such as water and space heaters; and</li><li>update Part 3.7.4, as a consequence of referencing the 2009 edition of AS 3959 Construction of buildings in bushfire-prone areas, including—<ul><li>applying the provisions to a Class 10a building or deck associated with a Class 1 building; and</li><li>the deletion of the acceptable construction practice; and</li></ul></li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_e079ea09-8939-433b-9f7c-131a90978b51"><title id="_71b418d2-dfa8-43ea-8036-9bef3840496a">Adoption of NCC 2011 Volume Two</title><p>The 2011 edition of the NCC Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of NCC 2011 Volume Two is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>include provisions for private bushfire shelters for Class 1 dwellings; and</li><li>revise the definition of Class 1b buildings; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_2349b505-f1be-42db-93e4-515e65d794ee"><title id="_9b9116a9-c398-4b68-bc4e-cfac574f4280">Adoption of NCC 2012 Volume Two</title><p>The 2012 edition of the NCC Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of NCC 2012 Volume Two is to—</p><ul><li> update references to other documents; and</li><li>include revised provisions aimed at reducing slips, trips and falls in buildings; and</li><li>remove the acceptable construction practice for masonry following the referencing of AS 4773 Masonry for small buildings, and completion of a 12 month transition period; and</li><li>restructure the acceptable construction practice for wet areas; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_dc7e6a4f-f625-445c-94d4-93af95789cb1"><title id="_a094df3f-6388-403d-b9c9-49f1001c1c85">Adoption of NCC 2013 Volume Two</title><p>The 2013 edition of the NCC Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of NCC 2013 Volume Two is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>include new provisions for openable windows to reduce falls in buildings; and</li><li>include a Performance Requirement and reference a Standard for construction in flood hazard areas; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_327a25dc-570a-4792-b8ef-9c2403b8d6cc"><title id="_82652095-4c47-4c1d-a1c9-38b167286707">Adoption of NCC 2014 Volume Two</title><p>The 2014 edition of the NCC Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of NCC 2014 Volume Two is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>quantify slip resistance on stair treads in Class 1 buildings; and</li><li>relocate the energy efficiency provisions for heated water systems to NCC Volume Three; and</li><li>expand the energy efficiency heating options for swimming pools and associated spa pools; and</li><li>include a new acceptable construction practice for hardboard cladding; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_c4e26eb0-c628-4610-b9d2-6e6fe1451297"><title id="_b460b526-04ff-454f-87e7-dc41776247d9">Adoption of NCC 2015 Volume Two </title><p>The 2015 edition of the NCC Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of NCC 2015 Volume Two is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>include a Verification Method for structural reliability; and</li><li>include a Verification Method for weatherproofing of external walls; and</li><li>include revised Acceptable Construction Practice for termite management systems.</li></ul></section><section id="_fa70f188-795b-4892-afcf-03f4a8e1fd8b"><title id="_57e87500-8121-4431-ad7b-759342d4cf2f">Adoption of NCC 2016 Volume Two</title><p>The 2016 edition of NCC Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of NCC 2016 Volume Two is to—</p><ul><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>amend the “Introduction” and “General Requirements” as part of the initiative to increase the use of Performance Solutions; and</li><li>include new Verification Methods for structural robustness and indoor air quality; and</li><li>include changes as a result of the Acceptable Construction Practice Review project, including the provisions for termite risk management, subfloor ventilation, facilities, light and ventilation and stair construction; and</li><li>include requirements for overflow of eaves gutters; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_665c35ea-d0b6-4ef5-a666-5375712fffa6"><title id="_7f970507-7e78-4da7-9056-6fec78cdaa29">Adoption of NCC 2019 Volume Two</title><p>The 2019 edition of NCC Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of NCC 2019 Volume Two is to—</p><ul><li>include the Governing Requirements, that result from revision of Part 1 to improve readability and are common to all volumes; and</li><li>introduce the use of schedules that are common to all volumes; and</li><li>include new Verification Methods; and</li><li>include changes resulting from review of acceptable construction practice, including amendments for earthworks, masonry, roof and wall cladding, fire safety and alpine areas; and</li><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>include minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_d6094570-7357-4932-bb31-0f161f21aeff" keep-with-next="true"><title id="_1945622d-33ef-498d-b3c5-31edb9d749a3" outputclass="none" toc="true">NCC 2019 Amendment No. 1</title><p>Amendment No. 1 to the 2019 edition of NCC Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p> The purpose of NCC Volume Two Amendment 1 is to—</p><ul><li>require that a process be followed to improve the quality of and documentation for Performance Solutions; and</li><li>require labelling of Aluminium Composite Panels; and</li><li>clarify that anti-ponding board requirements only apply to roofs where sarking is installed.</li></ul></section><section id="_81b690db-4caf-4572-b5a4-59539dd72af4"><title id="_718fd8c5-970d-4576-9568-553240a62bba">NCC 2022</title><p>The 2022 edition of NCC Volume Two was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of NCC Volume Two 2022 is to—</p><ul><li>include quantified Performance Requirements; and</li><li>include changes resulting from review of housing provisions, including amendments for footings and slabs, masonry, steel framing, waterproofing and glazing; and</li><li>include amendments relating to allowable encroachments; and</li><li>incorporate amended energy efficiency and condensation management provisions; and</li><li>update references to other documents; and</li><li>include other minor technical changes.</li></ul></section><section id="_cbefd419-e484-428e-9d7e-c20f2af39c7c"><title id="_cb788a69-27e3-456c-86f2-68255fc56a87">NCC 2022 Amendment No. 1</title><p>Amendment No. 1 to the 2022 edition of the NCC was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of NCC Amendment 1 is to—</p><ul><li>update the copyright and licence notice; and</li><li>amend variations and additions for Western Australia; and</li><li>amend variation for Tasmania regarding Part H8; and</li><li>correct errors.</li></ul></section><section id="_a4400ace-691f-4011-99bd-d0da56389a11"><title id="_e4f17928-eb3a-490a-94ad-26e49cc30ec1">NCC 2022 Amendment No. 2</title><p>Amendment No. 2 to the 2022 edition of the NCC was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of Amendment No. 2 is to align the NCC with the Access Code in the Disability (Access to Premises—Buildings) Standards 2010.</p></section><section id="_1f983878-5962-40de-a88f-368e7b2c39bc"><title id="_443cacee-0f4c-47bb-a63b-be89448d5fae">NCC 2025</title><p>The 2025 edition of the NCC was adopted as set out in Table 1.</p><p>The purpose of NCC 2025 Volume Two is to—</p><ul><li>improve robustness of Performance Solutions relating to structural reliability; and</li><li>clarify ramp types for which handrails are not necessary; and</li><li>incorporate a new provision for swimming pool drainage; and</li><li>correct errors.</li></ul></section></page>