<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><table-reference xmlns:xt="urn:xpressauthor:trackchanges" graph="None" id="_728c4e0c-e804-4558-a1bc-f8ce48ac4aa1"><num>1</num><title id="_fffcd658-fa16-42a4-bfbb-9513c7a7e4fb">List of amendments - NCC 2025 Volume Two</title><table id="_5b2d5821-79df-45fd-9189-9f0688a26051" keycol="1"><tgroup cols="2"><colspec colname="001" colnum="1" colwidth="216.00*"/><colspec colname="002" colnum="2" colwidth="216.00*"/><thead><row><entry>Reference</entry><entry>Changes and commentary</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001"><b id="_dcabc41d-505a-4af2-8abe-70242936f786">Section A—Governing requirements</b></entry></row><row><entry>A2G2</entry><entry>A new sub-clause added to specify that Performance Solutions for the structural reliability of components must be at least equivalent to solutions developed using the Deemed-to-Satisfy Provisions. A Note has been included to outline transitional arrangements.</entry></row><row><entry>A2G2</entry><entry>A limitations statement has been added that prohibits the use of A2G2(2)(c)—Expert Judgement—in Performance Solutions for certain Performance Requirements, to the extent these Performance Requirements relate to structural or fire safety.</entry></row><row><entry>A4G1</entry><entry>Multiple amendments, including new Notes and Exemptions, to permit the use of an edition of a document edition found on the register of alternative referenced documents as an alternative to the edition listed in Schedule 2.</entry></row><row><entry>A5G6(1) &amp; (3)</entry><entry>Multiple amendments to allow a building material, component or assembly to be deemed to have a fire hazard property where it differs in a minor degree to a tested prototype, as confirmed by an Accredited Testing Laboratory.</entry></row><row><entry>A5G6(2)</entry><entry>A new sub-clause has been added to specify methods for determining combustibility.</entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001"><b id="_95b65e01-939d-4ef7-a3d6-4cf3c9ede07d">Part H1—Structure</b></entry></row><row><entry>H1P1</entry><entry>Various amendments are included that improve the robustness of Performance Solutions regarding structural reliability by necessitating use of H1V1 and appropriate allowances to demonstrate achievement of specific reliability levels. A Note has been included to outline transitional arrangements.</entry></row><row><entry>H1V1</entry><entry>Revised to incorporate component variability factors, specify further design actions and align with amendments to B1P1.</entry></row><row><entry>H1D7(2)</entry><entry>Wind region B2 for metal roofing has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>H1D7(6)</entry><entry>A new subclause has been added for external wall insulation and finish cladding systems to AS 5346.</entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001"><b id="_baa1df3c-946e-4626-b27b-ab65c32979e3">Part H2—Damp and weatherproofing</b></entry></row><row><entry>H2P4</entry><entry>NCC 2022 contained a note indicating there were no Deemed-to-Satisfy Provisions for H2P4. This note has been deleted as a consequence of amendments to H2D2.</entry></row><row><entry>H2V1</entry><entry>Clarification amendments.</entry></row><row><entry>H2D1</entry><entry>Amended as a consequence of H2D2(2).</entry></row><row><entry>H2D2(2)</entry><entry>A new sub-clause has been included for swimming pool drainage.</entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001"><b id="_f30a457a-a39f-4691-920e-8fc955db03ab">Part H3—Fire safety</b>

</entry></row><row><entry>H3D2(2)</entry><entry>Amended to require that determination of fire hazard properties via test is to be made by an Accredited Testing Laboratory. A transition period has been included for this amendment.</entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001"><b id="_8725ed5c-c2e6-4aa4-9039-fbd42e909d61">Part H4—Health and amenity</b> 

</entry></row><row><entry>H4D7(2)</entry><entry>Amended to include AS 1668.4 for the verification of natural ventilation.</entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001"><b id="_d25a0f47-ec73-492a-860b-1845b1b69e79">Part H5—Safe movement and access</b></entry></row><row><entry>H5P1</entry><entry>Amended to clarify that threshold ramps are not subject to H5P1.</entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001"><b id="_bfa0ee56-8120-4141-a570-7181023233bd">Part H6—Energy efficiency</b></entry></row><row><entry>S42C2(3)(b)</entry><entry>Reference to the definition for ‘floor area’ has been removed.</entry></row><row><entry>S42C4(1)</entry><entry>Amended to clarify (d) applies for slab edge insulation.</entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001"><b id="_609a9317-a8ad-45e5-99b3-189ec4952ab9">Part H7—Ancillary provisions and additional construction requirementsPart H7—Ancillary provisions and additional construction requirements</b>

</entry></row><row><entry>H7D2(1)</entry><entry>Amended such that clause 2.3.1 of AS 1926.1 applies to boundary barriers.</entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001"><b id="_c6bfb696-f93e-4475-adb0-b20cbb320797">Part H8—Livable housing design</b>

</entry></row><row><entry>H8D2(2)(b)(iii)</entry><entry>‘Site’ corrected to ‘allotment’.</entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001"><b id="_ee4f380e-8586-4c6e-ab67-37ddc14507e7">Schedule 1—Definitions</b>

</entry></row><row><entry>Abbreviations</entry><entry>Diameter Nominal (DN) has been added to Abbreviations.</entry></row><row><entry>Symbols</entry><entry>Carbon dioxide equivalent per square metre hour (CO2-e/m2.hr) has been added to Symbols.</entry></row><row><entry>Symbols</entry><entry>Watt peak per meter squared output of a solar photovoltaic panel (Wp/m2) has been added to Symbols.</entry></row><row><entry>Allotment</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘allotment’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Ancillary components</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘ancillary components’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Cavity</entry><entry>The defined term ‘cavity’ has been amended to cover additional wall types.</entry></row><row><entry>Climate specific part load value</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘climate specific part load value’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Figure 2</entry><entry>Figure 2 has been updated.</entry></row><row><entry>Collected</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘collected’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Combustible</entry><entry>The defined term ‘combustible’ has been amended to require that determination using AS 1530.1 is to be undertaken by an Accredited Testing Laboratory. A transition period has been included for this amendment.</entry></row><row><entry>Condensation</entry><entry>The defined term ‘condensation’ has been amended to replace ‘moisture’ with ‘liquid water’.</entry></row><row><entry>Control layer</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘control layer’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Critical radiant flux</entry><entry>The defined term ‘critical radiant flux’ has been amended to require that determination using AS ISO 9239.1 is to be undertaken by an Accredited Testing Laboratory. A transition period has been included for this amendment.</entry></row><row><entry>Table 4</entry><entry>Amended to reflect updated wind classes B1 and B2.</entry></row><row><entry>Drainage system</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘drainage system’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Drained</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘drained’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Embodied carbon emissions</entry><entry>A defined term, ‘embodied carbon emissions’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Envelope</entry><entry>The defined term ‘envelope’ has been amended.</entry></row><row><entry>Fire hazard properties</entry><entry>The defined term ‘fire hazard properties’ has been amended to align methods of determination.</entry></row><row><entry>Fire protected steel</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘fire-protected steel’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Fire-source feature</entry><entry>The defined term ‘fire-source feature’ has been amended to include the construction edge or perimeter of another building on the allotment, which is not a Class 10 building, which has a use that constitutes a fire load.</entry></row><row><entry>Flammability index</entry><entry>The defined term ‘flammability Index’ has been amended to require that determination using AS 1530.2 is to be made by an Accredited Testing Laboratory. A transition period has been included for this amendment.</entry></row><row><entry>House energy rating software</entry><entry>The defined term ‘house energy rating software’ has been amended to include reference to relevant Volume One provisions.</entry></row><row><entry>Kerb ramp</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘kerb ramp’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Mezzanine</entry><entry>The defined term ‘mezzanine’ has been amended for clarity.</entry></row><row><entry>NABERS Embodied Carbon</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘NABERS Embodied Carbon’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Non-combustible</entry><entry>The defined term ‘non-combustible’ has been amended to require that determination using AS 1530.1 is to be made by an Accredited Testing Laboratory. A transition period has been included for this amendment.</entry></row><row><entry>Occupiable outdoor area</entry><entry>Explanatory information has been provided to assist with interpretation.</entry></row><row><entry>Point of connection</entry><entry>The defined term, ‘Point of connection’, has been amended to incorporate rainwater storage.</entry></row><row><entry>Rainwater</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘rainwater’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Redirected</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘redirected’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Rising damp</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘rising damp’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Self-draining</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘self-draining’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Small sized, low-speed automatic lift</entry><entry>The defined term ‘small sized, low-speed automatic lift’ has been deleted.</entry></row><row><entry>Smoke-Developed Index</entry><entry>The defined term ‘Smoke-Developed Index’ has been amended to require that determination using AS/NZS 1530.3 is to be made by an Accredited Testing Laboratory. A transition period has been included for this amendment.</entry></row><row><entry>Smoke development rate</entry><entry>The defined term ‘smoke development rate’ has been amended to require that determination using AS ISO 9239.1 is to be made by an Accredited Testing Laboratory. A transition period has been included for this amendment.</entry></row><row><entry>Solar Reflectance Index</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘Solar Reflectance Index’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Spread-of-Flame Index</entry><entry>The defined term ‘Spread-of-Flame Index’ has been amended to require that determination using AS 1530.3 is to be made by an Accredited Testing Laboratory. A transition period has been included for this amendment.</entry></row><row><entry>Step ramp</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘step ramp’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Stormwater</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘stormwater’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Structural substrate</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘structural substrate’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Sub-surface water</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘sub-surface water’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Surface finish</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘surface finish’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Surface water</entry><entry>The defined term ‘surface water’ has been amended for clarity.</entry></row><row><entry>Surface water seepage</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘surface water seepage’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Threshold ramp</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘threshold ramp’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Total Solar Reflectance</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘Total Solar Reflectance (TSR)’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Upfront embodied carbon</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘upfront embodied carbon’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Water</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘water’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry>Water services overflow</entry><entry>A new defined term, ‘water services overflow’, has been added.</entry></row><row><entry nameend="002" namest="001"><b id="_3336df57-99e0-4db4-a3d6-c08f3c84882d">Schedule 2—Referenced documents</b></entry></row><row><entry>AS ISO 717 Part 1</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS ISO 717 Part 1 ‘Acoustics — Rating of sound insulation in buildings and of building elements — Airborne sound insulation’ has been referenced. The associated note (Note 1) has been updated accordingly.</entry></row><row><entry>AS ISO 717 Part 2</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS ISO 717 Part 2 ‘Acoustics — Rating of sound insulation in buildings and of building elements — Impact sound insulation’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS 1170 Part 2</entry><entry>Amdts 1 and 2 of the 2021 edition of AS/NZS 1170 Part 2 ‘Structural design actions — Wind actions’ have been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1170 Part 4</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS 1170 Part 4 ‘Structural design actions — Earthquake actions in Australia’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1530 Part 1</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS/NZS 1530 Part 1 ‘Methods for fire tests on building materials, components and structures — Combustibility test for materials (ISO 1182:2020, NEQ)’ has been referenced. A note concerning existing tests (Note 2) has been incorporated accordingly.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1530 Part 8.1</entry><entry>Amdt 1 of the 2018 edition of AS 1530 Part 8.1 ‘Methods for fire tests on building materials, components and structures — Tests on elements of construction for buildings exposed to simulated bushfire attack — Radiant heat and small flaming sources’ has been referenced. A note concerning existing tests (Note 3) has been incorporated accordingly.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1668 Part 2</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS 1668 Part 2 ‘The use of ventilation and air conditioning in buildings — Mechanical ventilation in buildings’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1668 Part 4</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS 1668 Part 4 ‘The use of ventilation and air conditioning in buildings — Natural ventilation of buildings’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1670 Part 1</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS 1670 Part 1 ‘Fire detection, warning, control and intercom systems — System design, installation and commissioning — Fire’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1670 Part 3</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS 1670 Part 3 ‘Fire detection, warning, control and intercom systems — System design, installation and commissioning — Fire alarm monitoring’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1670 Part 4</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS 1670 Part 4 ‘Fire detection, warning, control and intercom systems — System design, installation and commissioning — Emergency warning and intercom systems’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1684 Part 2</entry><entry>Amdt 1 of the 2021 edition of AS 1684 Part 2 ‘Residential timber-framed construction — Non-cyclonic areas’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1684 Part 3</entry><entry>Amdt 1 of the 2021 edition of AS 1684 Part 3 ‘Residential timber-framed construction — Cyclonic areas’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1684 Part 4</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS 1684 Part 4 ‘Residential timber-framed construction — Simplified — Non-cyclonic areas’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 1926 Part 1</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of AS 1926 Part 1 ‘Swimming pool safety — Safety barriers for swimming pools’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 2118 Part 6</entry><entry>The 2026 edition of AS 2118 Part 6 ‘Automatic fire sprinkler systems — Combined sprinkler and hydrant systems in multistorey buildings’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 2200</entry><entry>The 2006 edition of AS 2200 ‘Design charts for water supply and sewerage (incorporating amendment 1)’ has been referenced. edition of AS 2200 ‘Design charts for water supply and sewerage (incorporating amendment 1)’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS 3500 Part 1</entry><entry>The 2025 edition of AS/NZS 3500 Part 1 ‘Plumbing and drainage — Water services’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS 3500 Part 2</entry><entry>The 2025 edition of AS/NZS 3500 Part 2 ‘Plumbing and drainage — Sanitary plumbing and drainage’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS 3500 Part 3</entry><entry>The 2025 edition of AS/NZS 3500 Part 3 ‘Plumbing and drainage — Stormwater drainage’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS 3500 Part 4</entry><entry>The 2025 edition of AS/NZS 3500 Part 4 ‘Plumbing and drainage — Heated water services’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 3786</entry><entry>The 2023 edition of AS 3786 ‘Smoke alarms using scattered light, transmitted light or ionization’ has been referenced. The note regarding existing tests (Note 7) has been updated accordingly.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS 4020</entry><entry>Amdt 1 of the 2018 edition of AS/NZS 4020 ‘Testing of products for use in contact with drinking water’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 4055</entry><entry>Amd 1 of the 2021 edition of AS 4055 ‘Wind loads for housing’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS 4859 Part 1</entry><entry>Amdt 1 of the 2018 edition of AS/NZS 4859 Part 1 ‘Thermal insulation materials for buildings — General criteria and technical provisions’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS 5346</entry><entry>The 2023 edition of AS 5346 ‘Exterior insulation and finish cladding systems’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS 5601 Part 1</entry><entry>The 2022 edition of AS/NZS 5601 Part 1 ‘Gas installations — General installations (incorporating amendments 1 and 2)’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS ISO 5151</entry><entry>The 2023 edition of AS/NZS ISO 5151 ‘Non-ducted air conditioners and heat pumps — Testing and rating for performance’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>AS/NZS ISO 13256.1</entry><entry>The 2023 edition of AS/NZS ISO 13256.1 ‘Water source heat pumps — Testing and rating for performance — Water-to-air and brine-to-air heat pumps’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>ASTM-E1980-11</entry><entry>The 2019 edition of ASTM-E1980-11 ‘Standard Practice for Calculating Solar Reflectance Index of Horizontal and Low Sloped Opaque Surfaces’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>EN14511-2</entry><entry>The 2022 edition of EN14511-2 ‘Air-conditioners, liquid chilling packages and heat pumps for space heating and cooling and process chillers, with electricity driven compressors — Test conditions’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>EN14825</entry><entry>The 2022 edition of EN14825 ‘Air conditioners, liquid chilling packages and heat pumps, with electrically driven compressors, for space heating and cooling, commercial and process cooling — Testing and rating at part load conditions and calculation of seasonal performance’ has been referenced.</entry></row><row><entry>NSF/ANSI/CAN 372</entry><entry>The 2024 edition of NSF/ANSI/CAN 372 ‘Drinking Water System Components — Lead Content’ has been referenced. A note regarding existing tests (Note 10) has been incorporated.</entry></row><row><entry>SA TS 5367</entry><entry>The 2021 edition of SA TS 5367 ‘Photoluminescent exit signage — Product specification, installation and operation’ has been referenced.</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></table-reference>