<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?Xpress productLine="ncc-clause" ?><clause xmlns:xt="urn:xpressauthor:trackchanges" id="_9425bc50-354d-4a8f-9c55-9b6253cdcaad" outputclass="ncc-clause"><sptc>A4G1</sptc><title id="_29c2dcb3-f744-458b-bb58-36cdfc162d46">Referenced documents</title><archive-num>2019: A4.0</archive-num><subclause id="_fd0b44f2-f063-475d-ba54-855ed58d4f3e" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_4720bdcf-5569-41fc-b45d-f6d8c4dfaf2a">SubClause</title><num>1</num><p>A reference in the NCC to a document refers to the edition or issues and any amendment listed in—</p><ol outputclass="alpha"><li id="_bd1a83c9-cf4b-4da4-82d1-a26ce710e741">Schedule 2; or</li><li id="_e226d896-c4e5-4291-8d76-6bbf09a6484b">the register of alternative referenced documents.</li></ol></subclause><subclause id="_544adbd2-a65d-4b34-98fd-85c19063a7f3" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_224293ce-77c8-46cf-b636-d8eb19b231c0">SubClause</title><num>2</num><p>A document referenced in the NCC is only applicable in the context in which the document is quoted.</p></subclause><subclause id="_656289c8-4136-4eff-9800-d958e3089508" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_eb25f09b-5019-4550-9e63-0ccc769b14ca">SubClause</title><num>3</num><p>Where a new edition, issue or amendment of a primary referenced document is not listed in Schedule 2 or the register of alternative referenced documents, the new edition, issue or amendment is not referenced for the purposes of the NCC.</p></subclause><subclause id="_a03140f5-3aa2-4b75-9aca-3697dc3e0f3e" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_319bd186-c48f-4b95-9538-bef6caf914c6">SubClause</title><num>4</num><p>Any document described in (1) is a primary referenced document.</p></subclause><subclause id="_ec4c0258-5017-4d8f-adae-f96d23403f9f" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_59ad4f57-a05c-4455-a0fe-1183be593165">SubClause</title><num>5</num><p>Any document referenced in a primary referenced document is known as a secondary referenced document.</p></subclause><subclause id="_5203230a-718d-4b48-a933-41ab17b172e2" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_281a88e5-b8fa-41d0-9580-d3a8856ecf04">SubClause</title><num>6</num><p>A reference in a primary referenced document to a secondary or other referenced document is a reference to the document as it existed at the time of publication of the primary referenced document.</p></subclause><subclause id="_da13e38d-34b0-4f29-83d2-6e5151eb71ff" outputclass="state-variation-insert" variation="TAS" variation-type="INSERT"><title id="_fe92e67f-00b9-414c-a8f9-68ae3b376194">TAS INSERT SubClause</title><num>7</num><p>All Tasmanian legislative documents referenced within the PCA are taken to be the latest published versions thereof unless noted otherwise.</p></subclause><callout id="_123b512d-c4af-4a1e-8574-25aa04c98151"><callout-type ncc-info-type="notes"/><ol outputclass="numbered"><li id="_7061fe02-d383-480b-b5a6-4c9a0e5231ad">The register of alternative referenced documents is maintained by the ABCB and is available on the ABCB website at <xref format="html" href="www.abcb.gov.au" id="_17094ed3-3357-4ce4-b85b-6b09c280cd8c" scope="local">www.abcb.gov.au</xref>.</li><li id="_5e381c14-8737-420e-b226-36c0549a6726">A document listed in Schedule 2 cannot be used simultaneously with a different edition, issue or amendment of that same document included in the register of alternative referenced documents for the purposes of a <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/d5440ff9-b49a-4154-8539-afc815034863/1236_1.0.0.xml#_2f02788f-8757-4689-b36e-e44d96524cc9" id="_925975d9-a727-421b-827b-169e5f4b2f64" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="abcb-glossentry">Deemed-to-Satisfy Provision</xref> or <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/d5440ff9-b49a-4154-8539-afc815034863/1506_27.0.0.xml#_a953dcf6-ebab-404f-a3f1-6d85f87ab898" id="_1dfa9555-9ab1-4159-a97e-5092fc8e0b52" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="abcb-glossentry">Verification Method</xref> provided in the NCC.</li><li id="_67fdadfa-fb17-4a82-ad5d-39cab370c660">For the purposes of a State or Territory variation to the NCC, a document listed in the register of alternative referenced documents cannot be used where—<ol outputclass="alpha"><li>an edition, issue or amendment of that document appears in a State or Territory variation to Schedule 2, unless permitted by the register of alternative referenced documents.; or</li><li>a State or Territory variation refers to another document that amends, varies or alters the application or scope of a document listed in Schedule 2.</li></ol></li></ol></callout><callout id="_fa9b6d9f-6788-4364-af89-2a9097bef81d"><callout-type ncc-info-type="application"/><p>A4G1 applies to documents referenced in the ABCB Housing Provisions in the same way as for documents referenced within any other part of the NCC.</p></callout><callout id="_43c397ba-1e86-4c6b-aa44-b9dccc40fde6"><callout-type ncc-info-type="exemption"/><ol outputclass="numbered"><li id="_f3967a47-4d25-433c-a687-c4ee29b146a6">Where the primary referenced document is listed in Schedule 2, if the secondary or other referenced document is also a primary referenced document listed in Schedule 2, A4G1(6) does not apply.</li><li id="_a3eb8a5f-46f6-4e41-9b6a-cd4112c8bfd0">Where the primary referenced document is listed in the register of alternative referenced documents, if the secondary or other referenced document is listed in Schedule 2, A4G1(6) does not apply unless the register of alternative referenced documents indicates otherwise.</li></ol></callout><callout id="_d83b3bfd-aa12-4fb3-9ebc-73f2e5774276"><callout-type ncc-info-type="info"/><p>The use of referenced documents and alternative referenced documents should be documented in building permits, occupancy certificates and other relevant project documentation and include the edition of the document used, such as the publication date.</p></callout></clause>