<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?Xpress productLine="ncc-clause" ?><clause id="_283c5ca2-2928-44b4-a37e-d7e7bc0cdec6" outputclass="ncc-clause"><sptc>C2D4</sptc><title id="_6ede2ba9-ea08-4626-b689-76b60001509d">General requirements</title><subclause id="_16864c32-9f43-429e-83fc-ba417e4b3a09" outputclass="subclause"><title id="_17f289ae-1734-439b-882d-be1c882459b7">SubClause</title><num/><p>A sanitary <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/d5440ff9-b49a-4154-8539-afc815034863/1249_0.8.0.xml#_25307451-c7e1-4167-b4de-e5a1af26694c" id="_6cc8e5c3-011d-4caa-823d-79058e5c0bae" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="abcb-glossentry">drainage</xref> system must be in accordance with AS/NZS 3500.2 with the following variations:</p><p><b id="_ec7aedad-63d1-4946-aca0-e0c8c67dc9d1">(a) For clause 3.8.2 Delete paragraph (b) and insert:</b></p><p>(b) the drains laid through footings shall be installed with an annular space of not less than 25 mm filled with a liner of flexible material. However, the drains need not be installed in such a way if the drains are installed in a building that is—</p><p>(i) classified as a Class 1a or 10a building under Volume 1 and 2 of the National Construction Code; and</p><p>(ii) in sandy soil classified as Class ‘A’ within the meaning of AS 2870-2011 (Residential slabs and footings).</p><p/><p><b id="_e099508e-626d-446d-af45-e5e1282ba0dc">(b) For clause 3.18 delete paragraph (d) and insert:</b></p><p>(d) A vacuum sewer system DN 100 downstream vent shall be connected on the main drain—</p><p>(i) before or on the inspection shaft riser; and</p><p>(ii) after the last fixture on the main drain.</p><p>The vacuum sewer system DN 100 downstream vent should be connected as close as possible to the inspection shaft riser.</p><p>(e) Vacuum sewer system and boundary trap low level vents shall terminate between a minimum of 150 mm and a maximum of 250 mm above ground or adopted flood level using one of the following methods—</p><p>(i) one 88° bend and a flat grate with invert level not less than 150 mm above ground or adopted flood level;</p><p>(ii) two 88° bends and a flat grate or vent cowl so that there is not less than 150 mm between the flat grate or vent cowl and the ground or adopted flood level;</p><p>(iii) an air admittance valve not less than 150 mm above ground or adopted flood level installed in accordance with Clause 6.9.</p><p/><p><b id="_9df9fe5e-c6b6-461b-8cf0-007541dd005b">(c) For clause 4.5.3 delete paragraph (b) and at the end of the clause insert:</b></p><p>However, if the reflux valve is being installed in relation to an existing building, the reflux valve may be installed upstream from the inspection shaft.</p><p/><p><b id="_b4ff11e6-01c5-42a6-9200-4ffea4957859">(d) For clause 4.6.2 delete paragraph (b) and insert:</b></p><p>(b)have each gully riser provided with a grating or cover of a loose; pop-out type to relieve surcharge and allow adequate ventilation to the gully riser; and</p><p/><p><b id="_6a5d14fc-662d-40c6-9e19-7bf3b6fcf400">For clause 4.6.2 in paragraph (c)(ii) delete “surround).’ and insert</b></p><p>surround); and</p><p/><p><b id="_dd3c18ae-b67d-424d-a1ae-d40c75a7827b">For clause 4.6.2 at the end of the clause insert:</b></p><p>(d) in relation to a class 1a or class 10a building within the meaning of Volume 1 and 2 of the National Construction Code — have the height of the gully riser not more than 600 mm measured from the top of the water seal to the grate of the gully.</p><p/><p><b id="_dc94fb63-a2f4-4308-8d40-3b473f2a4a00">(e) For Table 4.6.6.6 delete the table and insert:</b></p><p>See <xref format="dita" href="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/d5440ff9-b49a-4154-8539-afc815034863/10609_0.2.0.xml#_56149bb9-161c-464d-8548-d95cd52c77eb" id="_17d10486-107d-491a-ac98-f312d45b168a" referencetype="Text" scope="local" synctargettext="false" type="table-reference">Table 4.6.6.6</xref>. </p><p><b id="_efb99db8-ccf1-4458-994e-1557bbe2becb">(f) For clause 4.7.1 delete paragraph (c) and insert:</b></p><p>(c) on the downstream end of any branch drain that exits a building, between the building and the junction into the main drain;</p><p/><p><b id="_a75521be-c69a-4468-9791-7949ae94a477">(g) For clause 6.5.1 delete the clause and insert:</b></p><p><b id="_6b88cd46-c6f5-4f5d-b3f6-a4f6d756cda1">6.5.1 General</b></p><p>Each sanitary fixture and appliance must have a self-sealing device or trap.</p><p>A self-sealing device must—</p><p>(a) be in the same room as the fixture or appliance that it serves; and</p><p>(b) be accessible.</p><p>A trap (other than a self-sealing device) must—</p><p>(a) be in the same room as the fixture or appliance that it serves; and</p><p>(b) be accessible unless the trap is in the ground or concrete.</p><p>A trap (other than a self-sealing device) in the ground or concrete must not have—</p><p>(a) a loose coupling nut; or</p><p>(b) a diameter that is greater than the diameter of the outlet for the fixture or appliance that the trap serves.</p><p>A trap (other than a self-sealing device) that is in the ground or concrete must be directly below the outlet for the fixture or appliance that the trap serves.</p><p/><p><b id="_645f86ce-b8d0-454e-972a-ca4f00e1be7e">(h) For clause 13.9 delete the passage that begins with “if” and continues to the end of the clause.</b></p></subclause><table-reference conref="/tmp/QppServer/Publishing/d5440ff9-b49a-4154-8539-afc815034863/10609_0.2.0.xml" graph="None" id="_56149bb9-161c-464d-8548-d95cd52c77eb"><num/><title id="_2c732973-bbe3-4d74-ab40-afed3a821739"/></table-reference></clause>